Hey Max, what's up man? Welcome to Miami
and congratulations.
>> I appreciate it.
>> So just take us through the process of
draft day, man. I know it's a long wait
for you, but what was it like to get
that call?
>> Yeah, I mean I obviously like you know
the culmination of you know I've been
working towards this for you know pretty
much a quarter of my life. So yeah, to
to have my name be called is is a dream
come true and and to have that be called
in front of my entire family was was
really special. I saw a stat that you
had more wins than anybody in college
football on the spin move in particular
and I watched your tape and it was fun
to watch you get after the spin move.
How did that come to be kind of your
go-to move and how you developed it?
>> Yeah, I mean, you know, back in high
school, I wasn't the best pass rusher,
but the one move that I did have was the
spin move in high school and like, you
know, throughout college, like I've
added a couple other moves, but you
know, the spin move has been a constant
for me. Like that's just kind of been my
bread and butter. like, you know, I feel
like I pair it really well with like my
speed rushes and, you know, power rushes
when tacks are starting to, you know,
kind of kind of sit down on stuff, you
know, I'll throw the spin move in there
and yeah, it's been working out for me.
>> Appreciate it, Matt. Congrats again,
man.
>> Thank you,
>> Barry.
>> Hi, Max. Good to have you in South
Florida. A couple of things for you. Has
Jeff Hafley shared his vision with you
in terms of how he envisions using you?
Yeah, I mean I feel like, you know, this
this draft class in particular, like
everyone is, you know, that I feel like
there's a common theme between, you
know, everyone being tough, smart, and
physical. Um, and then also versatility.
Um, he hasn't he hasn't shared, you
know, specific details of of what he
thinks I'm going to be doing, but, um, I
think, you know, just just everyone he's
bringing in, like I feel like he's
comfortable with with, you know,
everyone doing a a job. So, yeah. And
also I'm going to ask you obviously you
have a lot of good attributes in terms
of size, can stop the run, can rush the
passer. Were you disappointed or
surprised that you lasted till the
seventh round and do you know why you
did?
>> Um you know at the end of the day I got
my name called. You know all all I need
is an opportunity to show my to showcase
my skills. Um so you know I can't I
can't be upset with the outcome. You
know I got my name called. So I'm just
super excited for this opportunity.
>> Thank you.
David.
>> Hey, Max. Congratulations on getting
drafted and welcome to South Florida.
Yeah,
>> thank you.
>> Yeah. Uh well, to follow up on Barry's
last point there, I I think we heard
from Dolphins personnel who said they
were surprised you were still there when
you were at in the seventh round, uh
will you use that as as motivation at
all going into your professional career?
>> Yeah, 100%. Obviously, you know, I think
you have a very very high standard for
myself. Um, and so for other people to
to maybe not see not see myself in the
way that I do, you know, that that
definitely makes me makes me a little
hungry. So, I'm going to come in there
and, you know, I'm going to I'm going to
show I'm going to show these people
that, you know, I'm I'm a really good
football player.
>> Cool. And I think one thing that that I
I I noticed in watching you is is just
how relentless you are uh rushing the
passer. How would you describe your pass
rush approach?
>> Yeah. Um, I think, you know, I'm a very
technical pass rusher. You know, I think
I have good good size and and speed. You
know, I don't think I have elite size
and speed, but knowing that, you know, I
got to be a guy who is super technical.
You know, I feel like I'm a guy who, you
know, I I'm going to study the hell out
of you on tape and, you know, I'm I'm
going to find your weakness and um yeah,
I just think I'm very technical with my
rushes and, you know, I eventually, you
know, you know, I set guys up and and
yeah, I'm going to figure out and and
find a way to win. Yeah.
>> Appreciate you. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
Chris.
>> Hey, Max. Chris Perkins, South Florida
Sun Sentinel. How you doing?
>> Good. How are you?
>> I'm good. I'm good. Hey. Um, I asked
Michael Taft this yesterday, the safety
that you guys drafted from Texas, of of
whether he considers himself an
underdog, and I'm going to ask you the
same thing because, you know, seventh
round pick, uh, but, you know, you had a
an outstanding career at Iowa. You're
kind of starting over again now. So, I
mean, you are in the NFL. You did get
drafted. So, do you consider yourself an
underdog coming into the league and have
you considered yourself an underdog
through high school and college?
>> Yeah, I feel like I've been an underdog
my entire life. You know, I was
undersized in high school and, you know,
I had to find a way, you know, even
coming into college. I was super raw at
defensive end. Um, again, super
undersized. I had to find a way to add
value and, you know, it's all I know.
So, no, I'm I'm real comfortable in this
position. Um, you know, I'm going to get
after it every single day because that's
all I know how to do.
>> All right. Okay. Thanks, Max.
Congratulations.
>> Appreciate it.
>> Isaiah.
>> Hey, Max. Isaiah Smalls from the Miami
Heralds here. Congratulations. Welcome
to South Florida.
>> Thanks.
>> So, my first question for you is, what
skill set of yours do you believe is the
most translatable to the next level?
Um, I just think specifically with pass
rush, like, you know, you got to have,
you know, a certain amount. I mean, you
got to have, you know, a good power, you
know, a good fast ball, good curveball.
Um, and I think, you know, guys that
have a complete skill set in rushing.
Um, and and always have an answer for
everything. You know, I feel like that's
going to translate the best. You know, I
feel like that's one of the best things
I do is, you know, you rar, you know,
you go watch tape, you'll never see me
get locked up the entire game. you know,
I always have an answer for something.
You know, I can always adjust and and
I'm going to find a way to win.
>> Um, and the next thing for you is
defensively, you know, the Dolphins need
some help specifically when it comes to
edge setting. I'm curious, what's your
approach to to properly setting an edge?
>> Yeah. So, at Iowa is a little bit
different. You know, we were, you know,
you go watch 1980 Iowa football game.
You know, it'll look the exact same
today. You know, it's an old school
defense. Um, but it works. You know, the
the the job up front, um, in Iowa is is
to to take up as many blocks and clear
up the back end, you know, as best as
possible, front of the ball to the
backend guys. So, I'm really excited to
to to to be a true edge setter. You
know, this is going to be, you know, a
chance for me to fire off the ball and
really show, you know, my tenacity in
the run game. Um, but yeah, setting an
edge just starts with violence. um and
and and pairing that with fundamentals,
which which I think I'm more than
capable of doing. So, I'm I'm really
excited to showcase my skills.
>> Appreciate you and congrats.
>> Thank you,
>> Joe.
>> Hey, Max. It's uh Joe shot at the Palm
Beach Post. Nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you, Joe.
>> So, I just did a map quest on uh
Southeast Pulk High School in Pleasant
Hill, Iowa. That's uh Kaden Proctor's uh
deal to Urbandale, Urbandale High
School. And and it looks like it's not
that far. Uh 18 to 22 miles. Did Did
your high schools play each other?
>> We did not play each other in high
school. I never got the chance to to go
against him. But yeah, we're we're real
close.
>> When you when you say close, you know
each other?
>> No, like close in probably.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Um, how do you think um, South
Florida might be different from Iowa?
>> Yeah, I mean obviously like the
weather's a little bit different, but I
mean Miami that, you know, that's a
that's a vacation spot. You know, I'm
fired up. You know, it's going to be
nice and sunny all year. I I'm I'm
definitely excited.
>> How do you think you might approach um
if you get a chance to go against
Proctor in the the practices? We're not
sure where he's going to line up, but if
you do get some reps against Proctor, um
he's pretty big, right?
>> Yeah. I mean, he's big, but you know,
every NFL tackle is big. I don't think
it really matters who I'm going against.
Like, you know, my my effort is is
constant. You know, I have one speed. Um
it doesn't really matter who I'm going
against. Um you know, I'm I'm always
gonna put my best foot forward.
>> Andrew Van Ginkle is from Rock Valley,
Iowa. I don't know if you're familiar
with him. He was a a late round Dolphins
pass rusher who found great success and
ended up getting a pretty big time
contract. Where is Rock Valley located?
And are you familiar with with Gink's
game at all?
>> Yeah, I know. Uh I know Injur Van
Genko's got, you know, a nasty little
spin move, too. Um I'm not gonna lie. I
don't even know where Rock Valley's at,
you know, pretty small town, but uh
yeah, I'm familiar with them. That guy's
a That guy's a baller.
>> Awesome. Good luck.
>> Thank you,
>> Travis.
>> Hey, Max. It's me again. I had a
question for you about the commitment to
Iowa and the fact that you didn't start
until your last year, but you didn't
leave. So many players don't get an
opportunity to play. They'll leave and
go find somewhere else where they can.
Why was it important to you to stay at
Iowa for your last year there?
>> I mean, for me, it was a no-brainer just
cuz like, you know, I came in with with
my group of guys my freshman year class
and, you know, we all grew up together.
We we had 5 years, you know, working
towards a common goal. Um, and that
feeling that I had last year, just going
out there with my boys, like these are
literally my best friends. And, you
know, we're going we're going to war
with guys. Like, it it was the best year
of my life. Like, it was awesome. Like,
just to showcase the skill, just
showcase the work we put in, you know,
for four years and and have that on
display was was amazing. You know,
there's no way I could have passed that
up. You talked about it being an old
school program and I kind of get the
sense from meeting you here that you
share that mentality. You feel like that
kind of prepares you for what the
Dolphins are trying to build here with
what they're going for?
>> Yeah, 100%. I mean, like again, you
know, I feel like the Dolphins are are
really the guys that they brought in are
tough, smart, and physical. Um, and I
and I feel like I fit that prototype
really well.
>> Perfect. Thanks, Max.
>> Yeah,
>> David.
>> Hey, Max. Me again. So, the the Dolphins
went into this draft with a perceived
need of edge rushers and they didn't
draft one until the fourth round and and
Trey Moore could play different
positions. They even list them at
linebacker. Uh what do you think of the
opportunity on this team even as you
come here as a seventh round pick?
>> No, it's it's a tremendous opportunity.
Um you know, I'm I'm not I'm not too
worried where they're going to play me.
I just I just want to do anything that I
can to help the team wins football
games. You know, that's that's my job.
That's always been the goal. Um, you
know, I got no personal agendas. I'm
just going to come in here and and
continue what I've been doing from for
my the last eight years of my life. Just
put my head down and work and and try to
make a positive impact on this team.